<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Defensive Lab Agency</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Defensive Lab Agency</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to backup and analyse iOS devices against Pegasus IOCs using Docker and MVT</title><link>/2021/07/pegasus-ios-forensic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/07/pegasus-ios-forensic/</guid><description>This guide gives you a step-by-step procedure to conduct forensic analysis of an iOS device using Mobile Verification Toolkit (MVT) created by Amnesty Tech team.
This guide is written and maintained by Esther Onfroy &amp;amp; Abir Ghattas.
Why? People are struggling to analyze iOS devices due to the complexity of the procedure on Linux. We have decided to use Docker because latest versions of iOS require the use of a version of libimobiledevice which is not available on Linux yet.</description></item><item><title>FinSpy spyware analysis</title><link>/2020/09/finspy-android/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/09/finspy-android/</guid><description>We have collaborated with Amnesty International for whom we have analyzed a new variant of the FinSpy spyware.
Executive summary By analyzing the sample we found what we suspect to be a new version of the FinFisher’s malware FinSpy for Android.
Even though the malware behavior and capabilities seem to be the same as what it has already been described in the past, this version goes a step further to hide the malware configuration and its capabilities.</description></item><item><title>Les applications mobiles de suivi du Covid-19</title><link>/2020/03/les-applications-mobiles-de-suivi-du-covid_19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/03/les-applications-mobiles-de-suivi-du-covid_19/</guid><description>Depuis le début de la pandémie de Covid-19, de nombreuses applications mobiles de suivi du Covid-19 ont vu le jour. La plupart d&amp;rsquo;entre-elles ne sont plus disponibles sur les magasins d&amp;rsquo;applications de Apple et Google car suspectées de relayer de fausses informations. Aussi, en cette période de forte inquiétude, il est primordial de ne pas laisser la panique prendre le dessus sur les bonnes pratiques d&amp;rsquo;hygiène numérique et de vérification de l&amp;rsquo;information.</description></item><item><title>Retour sur nos analyses d'applications mobiles utilisant Facebook réalisées pour le Wall Street Journal</title><link>/2019/02/retour-sur-nos-analyses-dapplications-mobiles-utilisant-facebook-realisees-pour-le-wall-street-journal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2019/02/retour-sur-nos-analyses-dapplications-mobiles-utilisant-facebook-realisees-pour-le-wall-street-journal/</guid><description>Le 22-02-2019, le Wall Street Journal publiait un article d&amp;rsquo;investigation détaillé. On y apprend que de nombreuses applications mobiles traitant des données de santé communiquent lesdites données à Facebook, que vous y soyez connecté·e ou pas. Defensive Lab Agency a été sollicitée pour conduire ces mêmes analyses. Au vu de la faible maturité sur le sujet, nous avons décidé d&amp;rsquo;expliciter une partie de notre expertise sur le sujet et d&amp;rsquo;illustrer les conclusions du Wall Street Journal avec quelques éléments techniques.</description></item></channel></rss>